# **Emmanuel Senft**

# Curriculum Vitae

#### CONTACT

Address Plymouth University, A216 Portland Square

Drake Circus, Plymouth, PL4 8AA

United Kingdom

Email emmanuel.senft@plymouth.ac.uk

Phone +44 (0)7751 689105

Website https://emmanuel-senft.github.io/index.html

Scholar https://scholar.google.co.uk/citations?user=Yw1tGf4AAAAJ&hl=en

## RESEARCH STATEMENT

Robots My research is focused on exploring ways to allow robots to learn complex policies Learning to in the real world, such as behaving socially in a Human-Robot Interaction. Learning Interact by interacting in the real world is a challenging topic, because classical approaches such as Reinforcement Learning or learning from big data can not be used because of their dependence on random exploration (leading to negative impact on the world) or the lack of large dataset for real world interaction. Part of the DREAM project, I am using Robot-Assisted Therapy and robots in education as scenarios to provide realistic situations, constraints and problems to guide the design and the evaluation SPARC, the interaction framework used to combine human control and robot learning.

## **EDUCATION**

2014-present PhD, Plymouth University, Plymouth, UK, Title: Teaching Robots Social Autonomy From In Situ Human Supervision.

Supervisory team: Professor Tony Belpaeme, Dr. Paul Baxter and Dr Séverin Lemaignan

2011–2013 Master of Science in Robotic and Autonomous Systems, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), Lausanne, Switzerland, Grade 5.5/6. With Minor in Area and Cultural Studies.

2008–2011 Bachelor of Science in Microengineering, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), Lausanne, Switzerland, Grade 5.29/6.

#### MASTER'S THESIS

Title Hybrid Optimisation with Roombots (Maximum possible grade obtained: 6/6)

Professor Auke J. lispeert

# SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 2017 Supervised Autonomy for Online Learning in Human-Robot Interaction E. Senft, P. Baxter, J. Kennedy, S. Lemaignan and T. Belpaeme - Pattern Recognition Letters, 2017.
  - How to build a supervised autonomous system for robot-enhanced therapy for children with autism spectrum disorder - P.G. Esteban, ... , E. Senft, ... , T.Ziemke - Paladyn, Journal of Behavioral Robotics. De Gruyter Open, 2017.
- 2016 From Characterising Three Years of HRI to Methodology and Reporting Recommendations - P. Baxter, J. Kennedy, E. Senft, S. Lemaignan and T. Belpaeme - Proc. 11th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (alt.HRI) (HRI), New Zealand, Christchurch, March 2016.
  - Social Robot Tutoring for Child Second Language Learning J. Kennedy, P. Baxter, E. Senft and T. Belpaeme - Proc. 11th ACM/IEEE International Conference on Human-Robot Interaction (HRI), New Zealand, Christchurch, March 2016.
- 2015 SPARC: Supervised Progressively Autonomous Robot Competencies E. Senft, P. Baxter, J. Kennedy and T. Belpaeme. - Proc. 7th International Conference of Social Robotics (ICSR), Paris, France, October 2015.
  - Human-Guided Learning of Social Action Selection for Robot-Assisted Therapy - E. Senft, P. Baxter and T. Belpaeme. - Proc. 4th Workshop on Machine Learning for Interactive Systems (MLIS), Lille, France, July 2015.
- 2013 An experimental study on the role of compliant elements on the locomotion of the self-reconfigurable modular robots Roombots. - Vespignani, E. Senft, S. Bonardi, R. Möckel and A. Ijspeert. - Proc. IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), Tokyo, Japan, November 2013.

with pdf

Complete list https://emmanuel-senft.github.io/publication.html

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- since 2015 Reviewer, Scientific Reports, JIST, ICRA, SBLI, MECH, IBERDISCAP, HAI, JHRI, IS, HRI, ICSR, HUMANOID, RO-MAN, TAROS...
- 2015-2017 **Demonstrator**, ROCO 318 Mobile and Humanoid Robots, Plymouth University,
  - Leading practical work on bipedal gait design and control for 3rd year students.
  - 2014 Construction Assistant, Biorobotic Lab, EPFL, Lausanne, Switzerland, Two
    - Development of a controller using a camera and an IMU as inputs to allow autonomous docking on a passive grid using Roombots.
- 2012–2013 Internship, EPFL+ECAL Lab, Lausanne, Switzerland, Four months. Development of a driver for a multitouch tactile wall for a permanent interactive installation at the Red Cross Museum, Geneva, Switzerland.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced Python, ROS, QML, C++, Machine Learning (Neural Networks and Reinforcement

Learning), Robotics, Nao, Human-Robot Interaction, Study Design, Academic

Writing

Intermediate Solidworks, ProEngineer, MatLab, C, JAVA, Pepper and YARP

Basic Robot Simulator (Webots) and Assembly

# Languages

French Mother tongue

English Advanced Conversationally fluent and technical

German Basic Level A2

Italian **Elementary** Level A1

Mandarin **Elementary** Level A1

# OTHER EXPERIENCE

2016-2017 **Comittee member**, *Karate-UPSU*, Plymouth University, UK.

Treasurer for the university karate club.

2014-2018 **Member**, *A+E*, Plymouth University, UK.

Mountaineering, climbing and caving student club.

2014-2018 Member, Karate-UPSU, Plymouth University, UK.

Karate student club.

2010-2013 Comittee member, Jdr-Poly, EPFL.

Association for the promotion of Role Playing Games and Board Games on the campus.

2007-2013 Scout Team Leader, Eclaireuses et Eclaireurs Unionistes de France, Douvaine,

France.

Team management and leadership, organisation of events with 8-12 or 12-16 years old

children with legal responsibility, member since 1998.

2008-2012 Member, Robopoly, EPFL.

Robotic Association.